Guide to the Peter E. Palmquist Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- General Research Files, 1822-2002; Series IV; 31.4 linear feet (75 boxes)
  - Carleton Watkins Research
    - Watkins in the 1860s and 1870s
      - Watkins in the 1870s
        - Watkins - Taber takeover (Box 112)
        - Mount Lola and Round Top 1879 (Box 112)
        - Watkins - Bohemian Club (Box 112)
        - Watkins - Agassiz and Japanese Ambassador (Box 112)
        - Watkins - Frances Moffat, Dancing on the Brink of the World: The Rise and Fall of San Francisco Society ( New York: Putnam, 1977) (Box 112)
        - Watkins - Railroad, 1869-1876 (Box 112)
      - Stereographs
        - Watkins - Stereo (Box 112)
        - Checklist Stereo (Box 112)
        - Watkins Stereo - Ruth Doty (Box 112)
        - Watkins - Stereo Miscellaneous (Box 112)
        - 272."Watkins Stereos," The Philadelphia Photographer, 1874 March (Box 112)
        - Stereo (Box 112)
      - General Research
        Material related primarily to biographical research about Watkins' life and work during the 1860s and 1870s, as well as repositories with Watkins holdings.
        - Brewer Writings (Box 113)
        - Park-McCollough House (Box 113)
        - The Fossat or Quicksilver case (Box 113)
        - 162. Morton, H.J., "Yosemite Valley," The Philadelphia Photographer, 1866 December (Box 113)
        - Frederick Law Olmstead papers (Box 113)
        - William DeWitt Alexander references to Carleton E. Watkins (Box 113)
        - Harriet Errington (Box 113)
        - Letters - Yale (Box 113)
        - New Idria (Box 113)
        - Geological Survey (Box 113)
        - Watkins San Francisco Bulletin 1874 (Box 113)
        - Napa (Box 113)
        - Watkins, C. E. (Box 113)
        - Julia Watkins (Box 113)
        - Watkins - Mt Shasta 1870 (Box 113)
        - Watkins- Yosemite Art Gallery (Box 113)
        - Watkins, Carleton E. (Box 113)
        - Interviews with Julia, etc. (Box 113)
        - 565. William Henry Brewer correspondence, Bancroft Library (Box 113)
        - Billings Mansion (Box 113)
        - Possible text illustrations (Box 113)
        - Main, William (Box 113)
        - Musée français de la photographie (Box 113)
        - The Sun House (Box 113)
        - Tang, Vicente (Box 113)
        - Toedtmier, Terry (Box 113)
        - Van Haaften, Julia (Box 113)
    - Watkins in the 1870s and Exhibitions
      Material related primarily to exhibitions about Watkins, as well as biographical research about his life during the 1870s.
      - Peter's Amon Carter Museum - Watkins (Box 114)
      - Amon Carter Museum (Box 114)
      - Muir Project (Box 114)
      - University of New Mexico Press (Box 114)
      - Watkins - Fort Worth (Box 114)
      - Watkins - Boston (Box 114)
      - Watkins - Saint Louis (Box 114)
      - Watkins - Oakland Show Reviews (Box 114)
      - Watkins - Oakland Museum (Box 114)
      - Watkins - Oakland Museum Lecture (Box 114)
      - Watkins - Book Notices (Box 114)
      - Watkins - Book Review (Box 114)
      - Watkins Exhibit - Sacramento (Box 114)
      - Watkins Exhibit - Vermont (Box 114)
      - Watkins - Palmquist (Box 114)
      - Amon Carter Museum Watkins Press Coverage (Box 114)
      - Watkins - Checklist (Box 114)
      - California Historical Society Quarterly (Box 114)
      - Carleton Watkins Stereograph Titles (Box 114)
      - Carleton E. Watkins Miscellaneous Writings and Testimony (Box 114)
      - Watkins Part III (Box 114)
      - Watkins Part II Revised (Box 114)
      - Yosemite Again Watkins's New Series 1876-1882 (Box 114)
      - Watkins - Appendix - Letters 1878-1949 (Box 114)
      - A. W. Ericson No. 2 (Box 114)
      - Watkins - Yosemite "Dome-topped Mountain" (Box 114)
      - Turrill (1918) C. E. Watkins (Box 114)
      - Carleton E. Watkins (Box 114)
      - Carleton E. Watkins at Work (Box 114)
    - Watkins in Montana, Oregon, and Yellowstone National Park, 1884-1885
      Organized under three headings: Montana, Oregon, and Yellowstone National Park.
      Research, draft writings, and correspondence with repositories related to photographs Watkins in Montana, Oregon, and Yellowstone National Park, 1884-1885.
      - Montana
        - Palmquist, "Carleton E. Watkins in Montana," draft (Box 115)
        - Correspondence, 1978-1981; 4 folders (Box 115)
        - Notes (Box 115)
        - James B. Haggin (Box 115)
        - Bancroft Library (Box 115)
        - University of Idaho (Box 115)
        - Montana: The Magazine of Western History (Box 115)
        - Copy photographs (Box 115)
        - Photocopies of articles, 4 folders (Box 115)
      - Oregon
        - List of Oregon stereographs (Box 115)
        - Copy photographs (Box 115)
      - Yellowstone National Park
        - Notes (Box 115)
        - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 115)
        - Copy photographs, 2 folders (Box 115)
        - Photocopies of articles (Box 115)
    - Watkins in the 1880s-1890s
      Material related primarily to biographical research about Watkins' life and work during the 1880s and 1890s.
      - Watkins's New Series - Notes (Box 116)
      - Watkins's New Series - Views (Box 116)
      - Watkins - Surveys (Box 116)
      - Watkins - "La Belle Cascade" (Box 116)
      - Southern California 1880 (Box 116)
      - Train Routes 1878 (Box 116)
      - Southern California 1877 (Box 116)
      - Bentley's Handbook (Box 116)
      - Arizona (Box 116)
      - New Orleans 1884-1885 (Box 116)
      - Awards (Box 116)
      - "Tour from Maine to California" 1883 (Box 116)
      - Missions (Box 116)
      - Watkins, Yolo County, baseline (Box 116)
      - Yolo Baseline (Box 116)
      - Monterey and Santa Cruz 1882 (Box 116)
      - Watkins - Hotel Del Monte (Box 116)
      - The Northwest 1882-1885 (Box 116)
      - Annie White Album 1886 (Box 116)
      - The Northwest 1882-1885 (Box 116)
      - Bentley's Handbook (Box 116)
      - Weston Naef album (Box 116)
      - Pacific Northwest 1882-1885 (Box 116)
      - Sonoma Valley (Box 116)
      - Anthony, E. & H. T. (Box 116)
      - Watkins - Kern County Views (Box 116)
      - Watkins - Kern County (Box 116)
      - Kern County (Box 116)
      - Watkins's letters to his wife 1880s (Box 116)
      - Golden Gate and Golden Feather Mines (Box 116)
      - Watkins - Tony Morse statement (Box 116)
      - Watkins - S. F. earthquake (Box 116)
      - 122. "Photographic Views of the Golden Gate Mining Claim Situated on Feather River, Butte County, California," Butte County's Historical Society Diggin's, 1964 (Box 116)
      - Watkins - Pardee Camp (Box 116)
      - St. Ignatius Album, circa 1890 (Box 116)
      - Watkins - Decline (Box 116)
      - Gently-Taber prints Watkins (Box 116)
      - Inventory (Box 116)
      - Watkins Album (Box 116)
      - Bibliography (Box 116)
    - Mammoth Photographs by Watkins
      Organized by Watkins's image number.
      Copy photographs of mammoth photographs created Watkins and related notes by Palmquist and Weston Naef.
      - 142 - Convent of Notre Dame, San Jose, circa 1869 (Box 117)
      - 143 - College Buildings, Santa Clara, circa 1869 (Box 117)
      - 1112 - Rooster Rock, Columbia River, Oregon (Box 117)
      - 1114 - View in San Gabriel Valley, Los Angeles, California, circa 1884 (Box 117)
      - 1116 - The Loop, Tehachapi Pass, circa 1876 (Box 117)
      - 1118 - Soda Springs, near Summit Station, circa 1875 (Box 117)
      - 1120 - Sutter's Mill, circa 1870 (Box 117)
      - 1122 - City of Helena, circa 1884 (Box 117)
      - 1124 - Panorama of Victoria, British Columbia, Christ Church, 1884 (Box 117)
      - 1125 - Reno - View West (Box 117)
      - 1126 - Minerva Terrace, Yellowstone Park, circa 1884 (Box 117)
      - 1128 - Golden Gate and Golden Feather from above camp, circa 1886 (Box 117)
      - 1130 - Cactus, Arizona Desert, circa 1884 (Box 117)
      - 1132 - Virginia City, Nevada, 1906 (Box 117)
      - 1134 - Salmon Wheel, Columbia River, Oregon, circa 1867 (Box 117)
      - 1136 - Virginia City, Nevada (Box 117)
      - 1133 - On the San Lorenzo, Santa Cruz (Box 117)
      - 1140 - Young Orchard, Palermo, Butte County, circa 1891 (Box 117)
      - 1142 - Pioneer Bridge and Weir Irrigation, Canal Kern County (Box 117)
      - 1146 - Sectional View of House Looking South (Box 117)
      - 1170 - Feather River Mine (Box 117)
      - 1172 - French Dam (Box 117)
      - 1174 - Gold Nugget (Box 117)
      - 1176 - Malakoff Mine (Box 117)
      - 1178 - Irrigation Canal (Box 117)
      - 1160 - General View of Malakoff Mine (Box 117)
      - 1161 - View in San Gabriel Valley, Los Angeles, California, 1884 (Box 117)
      - 1170 - On the Road to Yosemite Falls (Box 117)
      - 1172 - San Miguel Mission, circa 1876-1882 (Box 117)
      - 1173 - Warm Springs Hotel, Lake Tahoe (Box 117)
      - 1177 - Residence of T. Hopkins, Menlo Park, circa 1876-1882 (Box 117)
      - 1178 - Paso Robles Springs (Box 117)
      - 1183 - Victoria, British Columbia, from Government Building, circa 1876-1882 (Box 117)
      - 1185 - San Fernando Tunnel, circa 1876-1882 (Box 117)
      - 1189 - Peaches, circa 1876-1882 (Box 117)
      - 1191 - Crossing the Loop at Tunnel No. 9 of the Famous Tehachapi Loop, circa 1876-1882 (Box 117)
      - 1193 - Vine Hill, circa 1876-1882 (Box 117)
      - 1195 - Showing Method of Irrigation, Los Angeles County, circa 1876-1882 (Box 117)
      - 1198 - Cape Horn C. P. R. R., circa 1876-1882 (Box 117)
      - 1199 - Residence of T. Hopkins, Menlo Park, circa 1876-1882 (Box 117)
      - 1418 - Malakoff Mine (Box 117)
      - Mammoth Photographs (Box 117)
      - Other Photographs (Box 117)
      - Getty Research Institute Photographs (Box 117)
      - Notes, 2 folders (Box 117)
    - Stereographs and Landscapes by Watkins
      Organized by Palmquist into three subjects areas: Stereographs, Yosemite Valley, and Landscape Painters and Writings.
      Material related to stereographs and landscape photographs created by Watlins, particularly in the Yosemite Valley in California.
      - Stereographs
        - Watkins Glass Stereographs (Box 118)
        - Stereograph Checklists (Box 118)
        - Watkins Glass - George Eastman House (Box 118)
        - Watkins Yosemite 1-100 (Box 118)
      - Yosemite Valley
        - Weed Views of 1859 Yosemite (Box 118)
        - Description of Watkins Yosemite View (Box 118)
        - Olmsted - "The Yosemite Valley and Mariposa Big Trees" (Box 118)
        - Watkins - Copyright (Box 118)
        - "Views in the Yosemite Valley," The Philadelphia Photographer, 1866 April (Box 118)
        - Yosemite (Box 118)
        - The Yosemite Book (Box 118)
        - Watkins Project Images (Box 118)
        - Watkins Project (Box 118)
        - Sargent, Shirley, "Pictures from Yosemite's Past, Galen Clark's Photograph Album," California Historical Society Quarterly, 1966 March (Box 118)
        - Yosemite - Comments On (Box 118)
        - California Painters in Yosemite (Box 118)
        - Watkins - Early Stereograph (Box 118)
        - Brunet, François (Box 118)
        - Fiske, George (Box 118)
        - Watkins - Miss Janet Cooper (Box 118)
        - Stereograph Listing 1861 (Box 118)
        - Watkins - Yosemite Images (Box 118)
        - Watkins - C. L. Weed - Yosemite (Box 118)
        - Harris, W. (Box 118)
        - Fleas (Box 118)
        - Copy Paintings - Virgil M. Williams (Box 118)
        - Whitman, Nicholas, Letter Concerning Watkins (Box 118)
        - Yosemite - New Series - 1878 (Box 118)
      - Landscape Painters and Writings
        - Goetzmann, William H., 2 folders (Box 118)
        - Landscape Photography (Box 118)
        - Ayres, Thomas (Box 118)
        - Afterimage, 1983 December (Box 118)
        - Farquhar, Francis P. (Box 118)
        - Bowles, Samuel (Box 118)
        - Wilson, Richard Brian. American Vision and Landscape: The Western Images of Clarence King and Timothy O'Sullivan. Thesis (Ph. D.) - University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, 1979 (Box 118)
        - Luminism (Box 118)
        - Current, Karen (Box 118)
        - Greeley, Horace (Box 118)
        - Social Landscape (Box 118)
        - Turner, Frederick Jackson (Box 118)
        - Wilderness - Not Parks (Box 118)
        - Western Wildlife (Box 118)
        - Watkins - Early Reviews and Articles (Box 118)
        - California Visit in 1883 (Box 118)
        - Watkins - Ruskin Wilson (Box 118)
        - Watkins - Reviews (Box 118)
        - Ruskin, John (Box 118)
        - Robertson, David (Box 118)
        - Watkins - Thomas Hill (Box 118)
        - Watkins - Landscape aesthetics (Box 118)
        - Watkins - Relationship with landscape painters (Box 118)
        - Appleton forgery (Box 118)
        - Yosemite in 1870 (Box 118)
        - Letters between J. D. Whitney and William Brewer (Box 118)
    - Printed and Institutional Research
      Organized under two headings: Printed and Archival Research, and Institutional Research.
      Material includes printed and archival research, as well as material related to institutions with Watkins material.
      - Printed and Archival Research
        - Selover, A. A., letter to T. W. Park, 1860 January 10 (Box 119)
        - The Pioneer Steam Fire-Engine, 1860 October (Box 119)
        - Report of Frederick Claudet, Assayer, 1860 December 29 (Box 119)
        - Washington's Birthday Celebration, 1861 February 29 (Box 119)
        - Deposition of William Shew, United States v. Charles Fossat, 1861 June 27-July 9 (Box 119)
        - Deposition of C. E. Watkins, United States v. D. V. Peralta, 1861 May 8 (Box 119)
        - Park, Laura Hall, letter to Trenor Park, 1861 November 5 (Box 119)
        - Report of the Fourth Industrial Exhibition of the Mechanics' Institute, 1864 (Box 119)
        - "C. E. Watkins has opened a fine gallery", 1869 August 2 (Box 119)
        - Vischer's Pictorial of California, 1870 (Box 119)
        - Christmastide, 1878 (Box 119)
        - "Strange Phenomenon in Lake Tahoe", 1878 (Box 119)
        - "Mr. C. E. Watkins", 1880 April 22 (Box 119)
        - Watkins, C. E., letter to Frances Watkins, 1882 September 19 (Box 119)
        - Perkins, A. J., letter to Wallace Jacob Johnson, 1884 July 6 (Box 119)
        - "Views of Yosemite Valley", 1905 (Box 119)
        - Turrill, Charles, "An Early California Photographer - C. E. Watkins", 1918 January (Box 119)
        - "Early Photographer", 1951 May 19 (Box 119)
        - McDonald, Gerald D., "Photographers of Yosemite", 1952 July (Box 119)
        - Alinder, James, Photographs of the Columbia River and Oregon, 1979 (Box 119)
        - Smaus, Lou, Yosemite Stereographs, 1986 April 8 (Box 119)
        - San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, Art of Perception Exhibition, 1995 (Box 119)
        - Watkins photographs loaned to the Getty by Palmquist, 1996 February 20 (Box 119)
        - Watkins Colloquium, 1996 February 23 (Box 119)
        - Miller, George, "Plumbing to the Depths of the Spring Valley Water Company", 1998 (Box 119)
        - Lacayo, Richard, "Natural Wonder", 1999 July 5 (Box 119)
        - Watts, Jennifer, "The Photographer and the Railroad Man", 1999 (Box 119)
        - Berkson, Bill, "Watkins' Hours", 2000? (Box 119)
        - Johnson, Joe W., papers relating to Watkins research, undated (Box 119)
        - Reviews for Carleton Watkins: The Art of Perception, undated (Box 119)
        - Steiger Terra Cotta and Pottery Works, "El Capitan, Yosemite Valley", undated (Box 119)
        - Watkins research at Palmquist home, undated (Box 119)
        - Yosemite Stereographs 1861, undated (Box 119)
      - Institutional Research
        - Bancroft Library - Arizona Mammoth Prints (Box 119)
        - Bancroft Library - George Pardee Papers (Box 119)
        - Bancroft Library - Miscellaneous Enlargements (Box 119)
        - Bancroft Library - Photographic views of El Verano (Box 119)
        - Montana Historical Society (Box 119)
        - Nevada State Archives (Box 119)
        - Nevada State Railroad Museum (Box 119)
        - Provincial Archives of British Columbia (Box 119)
        - San Francisco Historical Society (Box 119)
        - University of California, Los Angeles (Box 119)
        - University of Nevada, Reno (Box 119)
        - Yale (Box 119)
        - Yosemite National Park (Box 119)
    - Watkins Research at the Getty Research Institute
      Notes related to photographic prints by Watkins in the collection of the Getty Research Institute in Los Angeles, California.
      - Photocopies and notes (Box 120)
      - Getty - 84.xm.171, 2 folders (Box 120)
      - Getty - 85.xm.361 (Box 120)
      - Getty - 84.xo.199, 2 folders (Box 120)
      - Getty - 88.xa.98 (Box 120)
      - Getty - 88.xb.97 (Box 120)
      - Getty - 92.xm.96 (Box 120)
    - Publications and Research about Watkins
      Organized under two headings: Publications and Research, and Publications
      Two groups of material consisting primarily of publications about Watkins, as well as related research files.
      - Publications and Research
        Organized under three headings: Numbered Publications, Publications and Drafts, and Research Files.
        - Numbered Publications
          Photocopies of publications about Watkin in folders with numbers applied by Palmquist.
          - 41. Blum, Walter, "One Man's View of the West," California Living Magazine, 1979 November 18 (Box 121)
          - 41. Anderson, Ralph, "Carleton Watkins, Pioneer Photographer of the Pacific Coast," Yosemite Notes, 1953 April (Box 121)
          - 49. Beatty, M. E., "C. E. Watkins, One of the Early Photographers of Yosemite, Yosemite Notes, 1936 March (Box 121)
          - 51."C. E. Watkins Art Gallery, Montgomery Street, Opposite Lick House Entrance," in Jacob Price and C. S. Haley, The Buyers' Manual and Business Guide, 1872 (Box 121)
          - 53."California Photographs in Vienna," Overland Monthly, 1874 (Box 121)
          - 70. Doherty, Amy S., "Carleton E. Watkins, Photographer: 1829-1916," The Courier, 1978 Winter (Box 121)
          - 90. Giffen, Helen S., "Carleton Watkins: California's Expeditionary Photographer," Eye to Eye, 1954 September (Box 121)
          - 107. Eric Hill, "Carleton E. Watkins," Stereo World, 1977 March-April (Box 121)
          - 111. Hood, Mary V., "Charles L. Weed, Yosemite's First Photographer," Yosemite Nature Notes, 1959 June (Box 121)
          - 114."C. E. Watkins" in James D. Horan, The Great American West, 1959 (Box 121)
          - 121. Huth, Hans, "Yosemite: The Story of an Idea," Sierra Club Bulletin, 1948 (Box 121)
          - 128. Johnson, J. W., "Historical Photographs and the Coastal Engineer," Shore and Beach, 1961 April (Box 121)
          - 129. Johnson, J. W., "The Early Pacific Coast Photographs of Carleton E. Watkins," Water Resources Center Archives, 1960 February (Box 121)
          - 130. Johnson, J. W., The Hearst Collection of Photographs by C. E. Watkins, Pioneer Pacific Coast Photographer, 1956 (Box 121)
          - 133. Kearful, Jerome, "Carleton Watkins: Pioneer California Photographer," Westways, 1955 May (Box 121)
          - 134. Kearful, Jerome, "Historical Watkins Photographs of 1861 Show Yosemite as it Was," Nature Magazine, 1955 June-July (Box 121)
          - 140."Library Gains Rare Collection of Carleton Watkins Photographs," California Historical Courier, 1975 November (Box 121)
          - 141. Lifson, Ben, "Notes for an Historical Fantasy," Voice, 1978 October 23 (Box 121)
          - 143."The Camera Obscura. San Francisco's Photographers," in B. E. Lloyd, Lights and Shades of San Francisco, 1876 (Box 121)
          - 153A. McCormack, Don, "The Views that Won the East, Photographing the Old West," The Sunday Magazine, 1980 July 6 (Box 121)
          - 159."1860 Cameraman," Oakland Tribune, 1956 December 3-4 (Box 121)
          - 164. Murray, Joan, "Carleton Watkins, New Discoveries," Artweek, 1980 March 1 (Box 121)
          - 164A. Murray, Joan, "The Watkins Albums," Artweek, 1979 October 20 (Box 121)
        - Publications and Drafts
          - Wendte, Charles W., Thomas Starr King: Patriot and Preacher, 1921 (Box 121)
          - Sandweiss, Martha, "'To Make the Exhibition Interesting and Mentally Profitable,' Photography in the Nineteenth-Century West," draft, 1988 January (Box 121)
          - Blanchard, Valentine, "A Useful Method for Hiding Defects in Skies," The Philadelphia Photographer, 1867 September (Box 121)
          - Early landscape lens (Box 121)
          - Field camera work (Box 121)
          - Watkins's camera technique (Box 121)
          - Watkins dark tents (Box 121)
          - Albumen printing (Box 121)
          - Watkins - cloud effects (Box 121)
          - Watkins - copy work (Box 121)
          - Watkins - wet plate (Box 121)
          - Watkins - traveling wagon (Box 121)
          - Watkins - "Photography as an industry" (Box 121)
          - Intro to Book (Box 121)
          - Intro Part 4 (Box 121)
          - Watkins - employee notes (Box 121)
        - Research Files
          - Giffen, Helen S., "Carleton E. Watkins, California's Expeditionary Photographer," 1954 (Box 121)
          - Calaveras Big Trees (Box 121)
          - Miscellaneous citations (Box 121)
          - "Frankie" Watkins (Box 121)
          - Whitehead, Margaret. "Carleton E. Watkins - The Dynamic Response: Wet Plate and the Landscape Photograph" (Box 121)
          - Watkins - Commercial Photographer (Box 121)
          - New Watkins Albums (Box 121)
          - Overton, Grant, Portrait of a Publisher, 1925 (Box 121)
          - Notes, 2 folders (Box 121)
          - Cartes-de-visite (Box 121)
          - Vischer, Edward, Vischer's Pictorial of California, 1870 (Box 121)
          - Yosemite Albums (Box 121)
          - Olmsted letter (Box 121)
          - Stereo-Mechanics Fair (Box 121)
          - Watkins - San Francisco (Box 121)
          - Watkins - Yosemite Mammoth Views at the New York Public Library (Box 121)
          - Martz, Barbara (Box 121)
          - Martz Stereo (Box 121)
          - Early Yosemite (Box 121)
          - Watkins Stereo, Park-McCullough House, 2 folders (Box 121)
          - Concord Library (Box 121)
          - San Francisco 1860's (Box 121)
          - Yosemite - Equipment (Box 121)
          - Watkins - First Trip to Yosemite (Box 121)
          - Photocopies - Yosemite (Box 121)
          - Tent for Outdoor Work (Box 121)
          - Yosemite Early Mammoth (Box 121)
          - Yosemite 1864 (Box 121)
          - Notes (Box 121)
          - Bancroft Library (Box 121)
          - Watkins - Yosemite Mammoth Peak, circa 1865-1866 (Box 121)
          - Le Conte, Joseph N. (Box 121)
          - Watkins - Yosemite (Box 121)
          - Brewer - Diary (Box 121)
          - Views at California State Library (Box 121)
          - Yosemite - Travel (Box 121)
          - Yosemite - Miscellaneous (Box 121)
          - 1864 Pocket Notebook (Box 121)
          - Watkins Mammoths at the Crocker (Box 121)
          - Thomas Starr King letter (Box 121)
          - Watkins - 1st 100 stereos of Yosemite (Box 121)
          - Stereo miscellaneous (Box 121)
          - University of California, Los Angeles, Stereo (Box 121)
      - Publications
        Arranged in Palmquist's orginal order.
        Material consisting primarily of publications about Watkins.
        - Carleton E. Watkins (Box 122)
        - Carleton Watkins: Photographer (Box 122)
        - California History, Fall 1978; Special Issue: Carleton E. Watkins, Pioneer Photographer (Box 122)
        - Carleton E. Watkins, Holdings at the Oregon Historical Society (Box 122)
        - "Carleton E. Watkins: Photographer of the American West" Southwest Art, March 1983, 1983 March (Box 122)
        - "Carleton Watkins: The Treasure and the Tragedy," Geo, July 1983, 1983 July (Box 122)